Guide to the Center for Advanced Studies Records, 1958 - 1969
Center for Advanced Studies Records, 1958 - 1969
- Persons Under Consideration
  - Chermayeff, Serge, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Chilver, Guy, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1962-1965 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Chukovsky, Kornei I., 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Clive, Geoffrey, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - D: general (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Daiches, David, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - D'Alverny, M.-T., 1962 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - de Tolnay, Charles (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Diendonne, Jean, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Dillon, Wilton, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Dinkler, Erich, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Doxiadis, C. A., 1966-1968 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Drever, James, 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - E: general (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Eliot, George, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Ellison, Ralph, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Elvey, C. T., 1963 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Erikson, Erik, 1960-1965 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Everton, John Scott, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - F: general (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Fielder, Leslie, 1962-1965 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Flew, Antony, 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Fuller, Richard Buckminster, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - G: general (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Gagnon, Paul, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Geren, Paul Francis, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Gielgud, Sir Arthur, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Gordimer, Nadine, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Grass, Gunter, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Greenewalt, Crawford, Hallock, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Grunbaum, Adolf, 1963-1965 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Guilbert, Gilles, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Guitton, Jean, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - H: general (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Halsey, A. H., 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Hamburger, Michael, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Hanania, Farid S, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Harris, Abraham L. 1963 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Harvey, Laurence, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Heller, Erich, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Heroys, Helene, 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Hochberg, Julian, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Hoggart, Richard, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Holborn, Fred, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Hopf, Hans, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Horn, Walter, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - J: general (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - James, David Gwilym, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Janney, J. Elliott, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Jepsen, Glenn L., 1962-1965 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - K: general (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Kac, Mark, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Keeney, Barnaby C., 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Kelley, John Leroy, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Koehler, Wolfgang, 1959-1963 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Kornberg, Hans, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Kron, Gerald, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Kung, Hans, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Kurti, Nicholas, 1960-1968 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Kusch, Polykarp, 1962-1966 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - L general (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Leyburn, James, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Lieberson, Goddard, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Lundberg, Erik, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - M general (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - MacDougall, Donald, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Markert, Werner, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - May, Rollo, 1959-1964 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Medawar, Sir Peter, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Miller, William Lee, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - N general (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Napier, Davie, 1959-1962 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - NEF Visiting Profs, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Neugeboren, Jay, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Nicolson, Marjorie, 1959-1966 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Novak, Alfred, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - O general (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert, 1959-1963 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Ore, Oystein, 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - P general (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Pfeiffer, John, 1959-1963 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Pinter, Harold, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Polunin, Nicholas, 1959-1965 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Portell-Vilia, Herminio, 1961-1963 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - R general (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Randall, Clarence, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Rao, Raja, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Reiser, Oliver Leslie, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Rojas, Hector, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Rosselli, John, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Ryder, Frank G., 1965 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - S general (Box 20, Folder 21-22)
  - Schwarz, Heinrich, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Sears, Paul, 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Stanton, Frank, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Starke, Werner, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Stone, C. Summer (Chuck), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - T general (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Thistlewaite, Frank, 1959-1962 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Tillich, Paul, 1961-1963 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Tyler, Royal, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - V general (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Van Der Goot, Anne, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Vorontsov-Velyaminov, B., 1961 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Voznesensky, Andrei, 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - W general (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
  - Ward, Barbara, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Waterman, Alan T., 1965 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Watts, Alan, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Weaver, Robert L., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Wharton, Clifton R., 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
  - Wilkinson, Elizabeth, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Williams, Carroll Milton, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Wilson, Colin, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Wilson, John Tuzo, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Winnington-Ingram, R. P., 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Wormald, Francis, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Wriggins, Howard, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Yevtushenko, Yeugeny, 1963-1965 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Ylvisaker, Paul N., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Z general (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Zassenhaus, Hans, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Persons under consideration, 1959-1961 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Persons under consideration, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Suggestions: general (Box 21, Folder 30)
- Recordings
  The Recordings are arranged chronologically.
  - Ernst Bacon, December 20, 1963 (Box 25)
    Two reels. Piano pieces. As recorded--not edited.
    Master and listening CDs made, May 2011.
  - James Farmer, May 10, 1968 (Box 22)
    Two tapes. Total length: approximately 1 hour, 20 minutes.
  - May 1968 conference
    See also transcriptions in Box 24.
    - May 13, 1968 conference (Box 22)
      Side 1 only. Nature of recording not specified. On same tape as May 13 Dr. Tratliff recording.
    - Dr. Tratliff, May 13, 1968 (Box 22)
      Side 2 only. On same tape as May 13, 1968 recording.
    - Dr. Plutchik on Emotion, May 14, 1968 (Box 22)
      Side 1 only. On same tape as Miller/Anderson recording.
    - Miller/Sam Anderson Theory of Consciousness, etc. (Box 22)
      Side 2 only. On same tape as May 14 Dr. Plutchik recording.
    - Private sessions: Dr. Yilmaz, Dr. Plutchik, Dr. Dahl, et al. presentations and discussions, May 15, 1968 (Box 22)
    - Professor Plutchik, May 15, 1968 (Box 22)
      On same tape as Professor H. Dahl recording. Not transcribed.
    - Professor Plutchik, May 16, 1968 (Box 22)
      On same tape as May 15 Professor Plutchik recording. Missing ten minutes.
    - George A. Miller, May 16, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Urban Crisis in America, May 1968 (Box 23)
    See also transcription in Box 24.
  - Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr. lecture, October 3, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr. seminar, October 4, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Dr. Joseph R. Washington, Jr. lecture, October 17, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Dr. Joseph R. Washington, Jr. seminar, October 18, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Father James Groppi lecture, October 24, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Father James Groppi seminar, October 25, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Dr. C. Eric Lincoln lecture, November 7, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Roger Wilkins, December 18, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Richard Navadoff Goodwin, aide to and speechwriter for Presidents Kennedy and Johnson, speaking about 1964 election, recorded after the 1968 campaign (Box 23)
    4 copies.
  - Transcriptions
    - May 1968 conference
      - May 13, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      - May 14, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - May 15, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - May 16, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
      - Correspondence, November-December 1968 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Brother Antoninus, spring 1968 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      This transcript appears to be partial. The recording on which it is based is not in the collection.
    - Urban Crisis in America: panel discussion, May 1968 (Box 24, Folder 9)